キメラアントの王討伐のため 宮殿に突入したハンター達
The 251-story, 991-meter
building is a mecca for fighters.
ん？
When combatants win a fight, they may advance by one class, and receive a corresponding reward.
俺の攻撃が効かねえ。 何だ？　こいつは。 フッ。 逃げるな！　答えろ！ こいつは何だ！
After reaching the 100th floor, you are assigned a private room. After reaching the 200th floor, you receive the right to challenge
the strongest fighters, the Floor Masters, in an intense
battle of survival.
俺が今やるべきこと！
Then, your brother is able to use Nen?
シュートを 助けることじゃねえ！
I need to know what Nen
and Ren even mean!
他のメンバーを 俺の能力で助け
I'll agree to the full learning process rather than a quick explanation!
１秒でも早く 任務を成功させること！
I understand.
メレオロンは　そんな２人から 断腸の思いで離れ
Nen x And x Nen
任務遂行のために ゴンとキルアの後を追い イカルゴも　パームを救うために 宮殿の奥深くへと進んだ
After Killua fought Zushi, the young Shingen-ryu practitioner, Zushi mentioned the four major principles.
「サテライトンボ」！
of those principles from Zushi's master, Wing.
絶対に連れて帰る
In other words, it tests your strength of will.
パームは　仲間の仲間
Burn
つまり仲間だ！　俺の仲間だ！
And the four major principles are part of a training curriculum for
strengthening your will.
いち早く　玉座の間に 駆け上がったモラウが
Strengthening your will? Training? That's correct.
さなぎとなったプフと 静かな戦いを続けていた頃
Focus Ten means to focus your soul to a single point, to increase awareness of your ego and goals.
ネテロは　王と共に宮殿を離れ
Express Zetsu means to express yourself in words.
ゴンとキルアは　ついに
Temper Ren means to temper that will.
カイトの敵である ネフェルピトーを
Act And Hatsu means to act upon that will.
その視線の先に捉えていた
Focus
Express
Temper
Act Ten.
俺を覚えているか？
Thank you very much!
俺は　ゴン＝フリークス！
Let's begin training. O-Osu!
カイトを取り戻すため
First...
ピトーには ゴンの言葉は全く耳に入らず
Yeah. The explanation made perfect sense, and Wing is clearly very strong.
頭の中は　現状をいかに乗り切り
But his story had holes. Huh?
かつ　王の命を全うするか
Zushi's toughness.
全細胞が　その解答に向かって 働いていた
He kept getting up after
I knocked him down. I was getting irritated, so I used all of my strength
during my last attack.
おかしい…
Brat!
臨戦態勢に入らない？
Crap!
わずかなオーラすら まとっていない あれじゃ　裸と同じ まるっきりの無防備
He flew out of the ring!
勝てると思っているのか？ オーラに頼らなくても
Even an amateur can see that
he's headed for the hospital!
ゴンが　みなぎらせている オーラは　以前とは違う
Oh! He stood back up.
いかに　ピトーでも
Zushi must be invincible.
完全な生身で対抗できる レベルじゃ　ない
Impossible.
ならば　間合いか？
However, the referee has awarded
a critical hit and knockdown.
この距離ならば 相手が仕掛けて来ても 十分に「念」を発動させ 迎え撃てるという自信
Killua wins by TKO, with eleven total points.
それならば　あり得る けど…　なぜだ？
Willpower didn't keep him standing.
そうは見えない
He's hiding some other secret.
あれは　まるで…
What's wrong, Zushi?
母親のよう！ 身をていして 弱い者を守っているような
Your Ten is unstable. Master... Hmm?
そんなバカな！
Why did you lie to them? Lie?
あいつは そんな奴じゃ　ない！
You mean my explanation?
けど…　なら なぜ　じっちゃんは…
Yes! The four major principles are
Ten, Zetsu, Ren, and Hatsu.
((中のことは おぬしらが判断せい))
But they don't mean what you said. Did you lie because they aren't your students?
あんな意味深な言い方を？
I didn't lie.
キルアが　必死で自分の直感に あらがっている時
Nen is an important method
for training your soul.
ゴンの瞳には 横たわる少女の姿と
However, it's true that I can't teach Nen
壊されたカイトが重なっていた
to someone who is not a student.
その人から　離れろ。
For example...
上に向けた手のひらは
With enough work, anyone can use Nen.
害意のないことを示す 精いっぱいの所作であり キルアは　それを知っていた
That is why you must be careful when
deciding to teach it.
頼む…　待ってくれ。
The rookies Killua and Gon have advanced to the 190th floor without dropping a fight.
ふざけるな!!
Get ready to press your gamble switches!
立て！　外へ出ろ!!
Unfortunately, your shove won't work on me. That's because
ピトーの思わぬ無抵抗に ゴンは　感情のつちの 下ろしどころを失っていた 一方　キルアは
I am as slippery as a snake, with sharp fangs,
to bite at your vital points.
現状をほぼ把握しつつあり それは…
You may sport a vicious chop, but you can't overcome these muscles!
あれは 知らされていなかったことが あったという意味
That's because... I'm totally ripped!
じっちゃんは　何も知らず 龍を落とした
Begin!
俺達の誰も存在を知らなかった
Critical hit and knockdown...
第三者！
Three points.
王が…　これも恐らくだけど
The winner is Gon!
自らを 傷つけることになった原因
Critical hit and knockdown...
なぜ　王は そんな異常な行動を…？
Three points. Knockout! The winner is Killua!
それは　彼女が王にとって 特別だから…
Once again, Gon and Killua have knocked
out their opponents with one attack.
彼女は今 壊されているんじゃ　ない 王の命令で治されてるんだ！
And both of them have
successfully cleared the 190s!
ピトーの治す能力は　「円」が 使えなくなるだけじゃなく
Both have advanced to the 200s! They've already reached the 200s?!
全オーラを　それに集中させなければ 出せない能力なんだ
Zushi. Master!
だが　その事実は ゴンにとって
Killua-kun and Gon-kun have
already reached the 200s?
マイナスの効果しか 与えないことを
Yes, they're amazing!
キルアは痛感していた
I need to train more...
どうすりゃいい？ 何て言えば…
Master?
ゴ…。 何でも！
I have no choice.
何でも言うことを聞くから！ だから待ってくれ。
Enjoy.
僕は…　どうしても　この人を 助けなくちゃいけないんだ！
What's the 200th floor like?
「何でも」？ お前の言う「何でも」って…。
Wow!
キルア　俺が聞いてるんだ。
The 200th floor is so fancy! Where's the receptionist?
「タスケナクチャ」って　何？
We finally made it. Yeah.
ピトーが選択した答えは…
What is this?
この人は　僕の…
All of a sudden, it feels like
we're in a monster-filled jungle.
僕の大切な方が 大切にしている人です。
But this is an ordinary hallway.
この人が　いなくなったら 王は　王でなくなる。
We can do this!
だから　待ってくれ！
This isn't working... I can't move forward!
助けたいってこと？
This is murderous intent, aimed at us.
「タスケナクチャ」って
Hey! Who's there?
助けるってこと？
Show yourself!
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
The receptionist's desk is over here, so please register for a 200s match today. You won't be able to register
ハァ　ハァ…。
after midnight, so please be careful.
勝手なこと…　言いやがって…。
Was she the source of all that?
勝手だよ!!
I can't tell. By the way, there are currently
チクショ!!
one hundred, seventy-three
contestants in the 200s class.
誰が…　誰がお前の…！
And starting from the 200s, all weapons are allowed in matches.
お前らの言う通りになんか!!
So please use whatever you have.
ハァ　ハァ…。 あっ。
Also, you will no longer receive
prize money in the 200s class.
ゴン！　ちょっと待て！ そのコを傷つけたのは 恐らく俺達のほうだ。
You will fight only for glory, so please understand that
if you're going to participate.
ピトーが　今　そのコを 治療してるっていうのも
Huh?!
「恐らく」？　「多分」？
H-Hisoka... Why are you here?
「恐らく」「多分」で待つって!?
It's hardly that strange.
待った後で　こいつが俺の 望み通りにするってのも
I love to fight, and this is a temple to fighting.
また　「恐らく」か!?
And why are you here?
「恐らく」！　「多分」！　本当!?
Just kidding... This was no coincidence.
ふざけるな!!　ふざけんなよ!! どうかしてんじゃないのか!?
I've been waiting for you. Remember how you ordered airship
tickets over the cybernet?
こんな…　こんな奴の言うことを 信じるのか!?
With a little effort, it's possible to determine where
and when someone will arrive.
信じられるわけないだろ!! あっ。 あっ。
Well, I knew you would come here eventually.
望むならば　右腕も…。
It's still too early for you boys
それでも足りなければ…。
to step on this floor.
両の脚も…。
How early depends on your efforts.
治療が終わった後で
It's too early right now. That's stupid!
僕が　妙な気を起こすかもしれない と思うならば
We just got up here...
治療に支障が出ない範囲で
I won't let you pass.
僕を壊してくれて構わない。
Not that you could, anyway.
頼むから彼女を　助けさせてくれ！
Wh-What is... ...this?
ぐぐ…。
naked in a blizzard, wondering why it is cold. If you continue to strain
your body, you may die.
ずるい…。
This is Nen?!
ずるいぞ　チクショ!!
He can stop us from moving
forward through willpower?
何で　そいつばっかり!!
Don't lie!
カイトには あんな　ひどいことしたくせに!!
Yes, I was lying.
ゴン！ 何でだよ!!
Though technically, I wasn't lying completely. I will teach you the truth about Nen.
何でだ!!
So retreat for now.
くっ…。
refused to register once before. So if he fails to register again, his commitment will be questioned, and he will be banned from participating.
ハァ　ハァ…。
Hey, Wing-san.
ふざけるな…。
by midnight?
最初は…。
That depends on you.
キルアは　いいよね。
But in most cases, it's simply discharged.
冷静でいられて。
The ability to build up a shroud of life energy is known as Ten.
関係…　ないから。
Shroud You can make your body harder, and considerably slow the effects of aging.
てめぇがテンパってるから 言ってやってんだろうが。
concealing your presence,
and recovering from extreme fatigue. Which brings us to Ren.
自分で最初に言ったの 忘れたのかよ。
Enhance A technique to create an especially strong aura.
ああ。 もう大丈夫。
However, I must admit I am
impressed by their senses.
時間は？　どれだけ待てばいい？
For better or worse.
完全に回復させるには ３４時間は　かかると思う。
If you attack a helpless person, with ill intent, you can use aura to kill.
ダメだ　待てない。
Only one thing can protect you
１時間あれば…
You must also learn to use Nen. You must use Ten for defense.
重大な危機を 乗り切れるところまでは治せる。
Block the other person's aura with your own.
お願いだ　頼む！
Otherwise...
１時間　ここで待つ。
Hisoka blocks the path leading
beyond the 200th floor.